Mss.Rec.84 Mss.Rec.84
American Philosophical Society
- Audio recordings
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of narrative given by Four Dancers, pgs. 239-240, 1971-09; 11-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:06; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) In the gap between this program and the program that precedes it, three or four sentences of material from the original text are missing. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 4.
  - Summary of work completed during the recording session, 1971-09-10; 11-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:31; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    The researcher and collector gives an overview and summary of the work that has been completed during the multi-week recording session. He also discusses the circumstances surrounding his original collection of Hidatsa medicine stories in the 1920s. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 2.
    Anthropological linguistics; Fort Berthold Indian Reservation (N.D.); Hidatsa Indians--History; Hidatsa language; New Town (N.D.); Oral history
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Bears Arm's narrative about Four Bears' life, pgs. 252-255, 1971-09-10; 11-07; 1.0 .mp3; 01:16:59; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) Signal cuts out on tape from 53:31 to 53:36. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 2.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Bears Arm's narrative about Four Bears' life, pgs. 255-256, 1971-09-10; 11-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:29:24; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 2.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Bears Arm's narrative about Four Bears' life, pgs. 256-257, 1971-09-10; 11-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:03; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of Bears Arms' account of the origin of the Sunset Wolf Ceremony, pgs. 410-412, 1971-09-10; 11-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:50:01; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 3.
    Anthropological linguistics; Hidatsa Indians--Religion; Hidatsa Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Hidatsa language; Hidatsa mythology; New Town (N.D.)
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of an account of the origin of the Wolf Woman bundle, pgs. 412-413, 1971-09-10; 11-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:42; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The researcher and consultant spend the first 6:15 discussing the consultant's medicine bundle, a variety of pine used for smoking, and the details of the story they are to translate. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) In the gap between this program and the program that follows it, approximately 1/4 of a page of content from the original text is missing. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 3.
    Anthropological linguistics; Hidatsa Indians--History; Hidatsa Indians--Religion; Hidatsa language; Hidatsa mythology; New Town (N.D.)
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of an account of the origin of the Wolf Woman bundle, pg. 413, 1971-09-10; 11-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:40; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) In the gap between this program and the program preceding it, approximately 1/4 of a page of content from the original text is missing. The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 3.
  - Translation from English to Hidatsa of an account of the origin of the Wolf Woman bundle, pgs. 413-415, 1971-09-10; 11-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:54:22; Bowers, Alfred W.; Driver, James
    This program consists of a translation from English into Hidatsa of a narrative given to the researcher in the late 1920s or early 1930s. The speaker sings a War Party song from 35:19 to 36:00. The text from which the researcher reads is found in his own book, "Hidatsa Social and Ceremonial Organization." (See Related Resource.) The Hidatsa language is referred to on the recording by one of its alternate names, "Gros Ventre." This Gros Ventre is not to be confused with the Atsina language of the same name. This program was originally recorded on the collector's original tape 81, channel 3.